[papers rustling]
Oh, your, uh...identification.
Congratulations. You are once
again a consultant for the CBI.
Thank you.
What about Lisbon?
Agent Lisbon
remains on suspension
pending departmental
investigation
of her actions
in the Red John matter.
'You'll be working with..'
Ray Haffner from now on.
He's an excellent agent.
Top-flight team.
- You're dumping her.
- Not at all.
Uh, we're conducting a careful
and scrupulously fair review.
You're rehiring me
and you're firing Lisbon.
That's a little...perverse,
don't you think?
No, see, you close cases.
Agent Lisbon ran a covert
operation that led
to the deaths of two police
officers and one FBI agent.
There just has to be
some accountability there.
My operation.
That was my operation.
'Well, that's
exactly the problem.'
'We expect better supervision
from our senior agents'
which is why Lisbon
is being investigated
and her team reassigned
to other posts.
Uh, Haffner and his team
already caught another case.
Here's the address.
You can hit the ground running.
No, I don't think so.
No? What-what do you mean?
Just what I said.
I'll get right on this.
[indistinct chattering on radio]
- Jane, right?
- Yup.
- Ray Haffner.
- Hi.
I'm-I'm hoping we can
jump in and do the job.
- Sound good?
- Sure.
Great.
'This is Patrick Jane.
Jane, this is Rick Tork.'
- How are you?
- Hi.
- Anthony Niskin.
- Nice to meet you.
- Hi.
- And Ed Masterson.
- Hello. Hi.
- Yeah.
[indistinct chattering on radio]
- I'll just..
- Absolutely.
[Masterson]
'The victim's name
is Markus Kuzmenko.'
'Got hit with something heavy
on the left side of his head.'
'No sign of the murder weapon.'
May I? Thank you.
[Masterson]
'Gardener found the body
when he came today.'
Coroner says it happened
around 11 last night.
Haven't found any witnesses.
Jane?
Hmm?
Any thoughts?
Yeah.
"The years teach us patience.
"The shorter our time,
the greater
our capacity for waiting."
That's pretty deep.
Is it Buddha?
Elizabeth Taylor.
This man's dead.
I'm all but certain of it.
What?
[sighs]
Alright then.
[theme music]
Thank you.
Mmm.
How's the arm?
Better. Yeah, physical
therapy's helping.
Good.
[sighs]
Tell me, uh
what do you know about
this guy Ray Haffner?
You're back at work?
Yeah, you know,
just consulting.
Haffner, uh..
...word is he's tough,
by the book.
I think he started out
in the FBI organized
crime division.
He had a couple
of high-profile busts
using wiretaps and creative
surveillance techniques.
Surveillance, huh?
- Yeah.
- Hmm.
Why do you wanna know?
Eh, just curious.
- Oh.
- Can I take this?
- You're leaving?
- Yeah, new case.
I, uh, I gotta man the phones,
hit the sidewalk.
- You know how it is.
- Yeah, I know.
- Thanks for coming by.
- Pleasure.
Yeah.
Just so you know,
Jane, I'm okay.
About?
Losing my job.
I'm not gonna say
I like it
but we got Red John.
It was worth it.
Don't be silly.
A, you haven't lost your job.
The hearing's a formality.
And B, we didn't
get Red John.
Timothy Carter told
you he was Red John.
He lied.
'Carter must've known him'
because he told me things that
only my wife and daughter's
killer could know.
But he's not the man.
- That man's still out there.
- Jane.
Someone told that security
guard to take Carter's gun
and phone, then killed him.
Who would do that
besides Red John?
Ergo, Timothy Carter
is not Red John.
Carter had to have known
there was a possibility
you'd kill him.
You always said you would.
So maybe he asked
a guard to take the gun
and the cell phone
if you did.
- Why?
- To mess with your head.
And it's working.
You're looking for a man
you already killed.
Carter's wife is in custody.
- 'She said anything?'
- Nothing.
When she does talk,
you know what she'll say?
That you shot
and killed Red John.
Good for you.
No.
Thanks for the tea.
What do you mean?
Uh, lovely to see you.
Keep working that bum wing.
Keys, change, anything metal.
Thank you.
[Rigsby]
Thanks.
- Jane.
- New assignment?
Just temporary.
Security's shorthanded.
At least that's
what they tell me.
Cho got a call today. Not sure
where they're putting him.
Grace is still waiting to hear.
At least we still have jobs.
You, uh, talk to Lisbon?
Uh, yes.
We're gonna have a..
...a little secret
meeting later.
- Tell Cho and Van Pelt.
- Secret meeting?
- About what?
- I'll tell you then.
Keys.
[instrumental music]
Hey, Tork, you're still
20 short on Tuesday's dinner.
Man up, my brother.
Yeah.
Jane, heard you used
to be in the circus.
- Is that right?
- Well, um, not exactly.
I like your shoes.
Yeah.
Hey.
I doubt Niskin meant
anything, by the way.
What do you mean?
"You're short." "Man up."
I don't think
he was referring to..
No.
I mean..
...no.
What have we got on the victim?
Kuzmenko was a naturalized
citizen originally from Estonia.
Was a swimmer on
the Estonian National Swim Team
came over to the US 2002,
no family here.
Stop playing with that little
ball. You're driving me crazy.
[Masterson]
He worked as a personal trainer
at a gym called Work-It.
'Got his picture
off their web site.'
I know that gym.
A lot of bigwigs work out there.
Hey. Jane.
Your thing's reading people.
What's this guy say to you?
I'd guess he was a narcissist
and a serial seducer.
How do you get that?
A jock with manicured nails
too much cologne,
too tight of pants
and he drives
a 20-year-old muscle car.
Okay. We'll see
if that's useful.
Masterson, you and Tork, you
cover Kuzmenko's neighborhood.
Niskin, you run his
phone and e-mails.
- I'll cover the gym.
- I'll go with you.
Sure. You can come.
Agent Haffner,
you asked to see me?
Yeah, Cho, let's talk in my
office. Meet you at the gym.
Sit down.
I saw your old team member
downstairs...Rigsby?
- 'That's tough.'
- I guess.
I know your reputation, Cho.
I read your file.
'You're a good cop'
but this Red John thing
really pissed Bertram off.
Puts you in a bad spot.
- What's your take on Jane?
- What do you mean?
- You trust him?
- 'Depends.'
Think he's smarter than you?
Yes.
- Think he's smarter than me?
- Yes.
You're probably right.
I read Jane's file.
I know what'll happen.
He's gonna go behind my back..
...lie to me,
run a scam on me, right?
- Pretty much.
- 'He's also gonna close cases.'
I get that too.
I can work with Jane.
I just need some help
'someone who knows him, someone
who can tell me what's going on'
warn me when something's coming.
'I'm not talking about
betraying a confidence.'
- I wanna be kept in the loop.
- What's the difference?
You help me, you're
at your desk working cases.
You don't, you're
downstairs working the lobby
with your pal Rigsby.
Where doyouwant to be?
Here.
'Glad to hear it.'
Here's the case file.
Good to have you aboard, Cho.
[intense music]
[phone ringing]
Oh. Just admiring your son.
He as tall as you?
No, no.
He's just nine years old.
Right. So, what, he's
about, uh, Tork's size?
[Niskin laughing]
[laughing]
No, man. No,
Tork's not that short.
No, my little man's probably
about, like, right here.
[Niskin laughing]
Hey.
Was Niskin just
talking about me?
Yeah, I-I gotta make
an important phone call.
Son of a bitch.
Hi. I need some help
locating a special item.
Gym's owner is Jocelyn Chapin.
If you don't mind,
I'll take lead.
- Lead. Sure.
- Good.
Ms. Chapin?
Ms. Chapin, hi.
Agent Ray Haffner, CBI.
This is Patrick Jane.
- He's a consultant.
- Hi.
- I can't believe what happened.
- I understand.
How long had
Kuzmenko worked here?
Uh, almost nine years.
He started here
when he got to the US.
- He get along with people?
- Yeah, everybody.
Markus was a real people person,
just charming.
You couldn't say no to him.
So was he having any
troubles recently or..
Not that I know of. Uh..
Um..
[weights clanking]
- Mike.
- Yeah?
This-this is Mike Villanueva.
He and Markus were friends.
These are, uh, agents from CBI.
Oh. Oh, it's crazy, huh?
Yeah, we're all
pretty racked up..
Yeah, did Markus mention
any other difficulties
that he was having,
money, other issues?
No. No, he was doing great.
Ooh. Feeling that. Yeah.
- We boring you, Jane?
- Nope. Not at all.
[grunts]
[clanks]
Sorry.
I thought you were
taking lead on this.
How many clients was
Kuzmenko sleeping with?
- Excuse me?
- You said he was charming.
Good-looker. He must've
had his pick of the bunch.
I, uh, I gotta get
back to my client now.
Uh, I have a firm
policy against that.
Doesn't answer the question.
Listen, a lot
of prominent people
come here, alright?
Politicians,
politicians' wives
and frankly, they
expect some discretion.
Yeah, we don't really care.
Answer his question.
Yeah, I-I heard rumors about
Markus and some of his clients.
If they were true, I would've
had to fire him.
I didn't wanna do that.
Markus was the most
successful trainer that we had
so I-I didn't ask.
I don't have any names.
Except your own.
Yeah.
Yeah, a long time ago
very, very briefly,
Markus and I had a thing.
A thing?
Nothing serious.
- We were friends.
- Oh. Okay.
I'm gonna need the names
of all of Kuzmenko's clients.
[instrumental music]
Hi.
Lovely rings you have.
Thanks.
Expensive, I expect.
Your husband must
be very generous.
Yeah. Do you mind?
Just, uh, one more thing.
Markus Kuzmenko
more of a gentle lover
or a brute?
[woman grunts]
[female #1]
'Oh! Are you alright?'
- You okay?
- Man down!
[door opening]
[door closes]
Your Mr. Jane,
how did he know?
Your eyes were puffy.
He could tell you'd been crying.
Does my husband have
to find out about this?
Depends on what you say.
[sighs]
It happened
a few months back.
Markus was coming
by my house once a week
to work on my abs.
He was so funny and charming
with a faintly...wicked quality.
Amoral, you know what I mean?
Unaware of moral precepts
as opposed
to being purposely bad.
'It can be a very
attractive quality.'
My husband's not like that.
Amoral, I mean.
Markus never hit on me.
I think I seduced him.
How long did
the relationship last?
Twice.
Markus wasn't a relationship.
If it was a just a fling
a couple months back
why were you crying
this morning?
He's dead.
It's sad.
Your phone records show
Markus called you last week.
'You sure
the relationship was over?'
Um..
...Markus said that
he had a business venture
he wanted to talk to my husband
and me about investing in.
[sighs]
It didn't occur to him that
that would be
an awkward conversation.
What was the business?
I don't know.
I told him
we couldn't discuss it.
[sighs]
So what about my husband?
There's a pretty good chance
we won't need to talk to him.
I'd hate for him
to have to find out
although a little bit,
I wish he would.
- Should we keep an eye on her?
- She seemed sincere to me.
Eh, she's a timid
suburban adulteress.
The only thing
she's killed lately
is a bottle of chardonnay.
[indistinct chattering on radio]
Niskin! You think this is funny?
What do you mean?
I just found these
on my desk with a note.
"Tork, try theselifts."
That funny to you?
[laughing]
I got nothing
to do with that, man.
I wear lifts,
so I'm a joke?
I don't know
about your lifts
but, yes, these are
real funny, man.
[both grunting]
[shattering]
- Come on, come on.
- Help.
- Break it up!
- My money's on the little guy.
I was engaged
to this guy, Craig.
You know, he seemed
like a good person.
We were happy.
Then I found out
that he was an assassin
for a serial killer
named Red John
and he tried to...kill me
and some other people, so..
I had to shoot him.
Tell me, how it does
it feel telling that
recounting it?
Not good. Pretty bad.
Can you elaborate?
Can I ask, how long does
this therapy usually last?
'It depends.
There's no set calendar.'
I'm sensing
hesitation on your part.
I guess..
...I just don't believe
that this will really work.
Talking about it.
What's the point?
Grace, somebody you trusted
and loved betrayed you
betrayed you so badly,
you had to take his life.
That needs to be talked about.
[chuckles]
It could've been worse.
I could've married him.
[cell phone ringing]
No phone calls during session.
That's a rule.
It's work. I gotta take this.
Sorry.
Van Pelt.
I can be there in 15 minutes.
Who should I report to?
Since Agent Tork has been
removed from active duty
I assumed you would
want to replace him.
Was I incorrect?
[instrumental music]
- Agent?
- No, you were not.
We could, uh, definitely
use another set of hands.
- Go in. We'll put you to work.
- Thank you, sir.
Alright.
Everything alright, agent?
Oh, yeah. Excuse me.
That was a nice game
you ran on Tork.
Hmm. Tork.
He was angry with
everybody taller than him.
Certain to burst eventually.
You wanted my attention.
You got my attention.
But if you try to run
another game on me or my people
we're gonna have a problem.
You know that Babe Ruth
wore a cabbage leaf
under his cap
to keep himself cool?
Changed it
every other inning.
- Agent?
- Yeah.
The night before the murder,
a woman called in
a suspicious man in a car
near Kuzmenko's house.
- Said he'd been there a while.
- She get the plate?
Belongs to Mike Villanueva.
Mike, when we talked,
you didn't mention visiting
your buddy Markus' house
right before he got killed.
I didn't wanna talk about
it in front of my boss.
Why are you worried
about your boss?
Business is down at the gym.
Jocelyn's on us
to bring in new clients.
Anyone who loses
clients is in trouble.
And you're losing clients.
No.
[chuckles]
No, I'm not.
Was Markus stealing
your clients?
Yeah. Basically.
Look, Markus got
the looks and the talk
so people wanna
work with him.
He doesn't push
them like I do.
I work 'em hard.
And you know what I get?
Five clients signing up
with Markus in a month.
You went to Markus'
house to confront him.
- I had to have it out with him.
- What happened?
'Nothing. He apologized.'
He took the clients
'cause he needed the cash.
But he'd gotten money. He didn't
need the extra clients anymore.
Then we went into his house
and got wasted.
[chuckles]
And that's Markus, man.
Went there to punch him,
ended up partying.
- What'd he need the money for?
- He wouldn't tell me.
Said that nobody
at the gym could know.
Where'd he get the cash?
He wouldn't tell me.
But, uh..
...I got a feeling..
...from the way he talked..
...it wasn't anyplace good.
The question is, what did
Kuzmenko need money for?
- And who did he get it from?
- That's two questions.
- Excuse me?
- Two questions.
Kuzmenko's boss at the gym,
Jocelyn Chapin
sent over a list of his clients.
There are some pretty
high-powered people on it.
State senator, assemblyman,
people working for the governor.
- It's the names I recognized.
- There's a lot of women here.
[Haffner]
'Some of them would pay to keep
an affair with Kuzmenko quiet.'
Think Kuzmenko slept with one
of them then blackmailed her.
Maybe. What do you think, Jane?
Mmm..
Well, I wanna pursue it.
Look for the money Kuzmenko got.
If it's not in his bank account,
check other accounts
'safety deposit boxes..'
Okay.
Cho, we'll work
through this list
starting with
his most recent clients
try identifying
who he was sleeping with.
Where are you going?
Uh, I thought I'd just go
over to Kuzmenko's house
take a little look around.
- Why?
- It's what I do.
Not alone.
Masterson, go with him.
- Okay.
- Keep an eye on him.
Yep.
Okeydokey.
So what are you
looking for?
[Jane]
'Whatever's here to see.'
[Masterson]
'We already went
through the house.'
- 'We didn't find anything.'
- I'm sure you didn't.
Pretty dull, yeah?
If you wanna get a coffee,
I won't tell Haffner.
Yeah, I'm gonna go do that.
[scoffs]
Suit yourself.
Some more of this
tottering around.
'See, me...uh..'
...I like to take
a break now and then.
A moment to, uh, rest and relax.
Take it easy.
Close the eyes..
...and shut out the day.
'Rest..'
'...and relax.'
Try not to see anything..
...or hear anything.
'Let time stop.'
'Rest..'
...and relax.
[instrumental music]
[thud]
- What happened?
- Huh? Nothing.
You did something to me,
didn't you?
You hypnotized me.
[chuckles]
That's absurd.
You know that only weak-minded
and easily manipulated
people can be hypnotized.
Yeah, we're leaving.
- I'm not finished.
- Yes, you are.
Okay.
[instrumental music]
[intense music]
[beeping]
[phone rings]
- 'Hello?'
- Laroche.
- 'Yes.'
- Hi. It's Lisbon.
I wanted to ask a favor.
It's about Sally Carter.
Sir?
I'm busy, agent.
Sorry, but there's
nothing unusual
in Kuzmenko's checking
or savings accounts.
- I found something else though.
- 'What?'
A couple days before he
was killed, Kuzmenko made
four phone calls
to an Oleg Mostovoi.
He's not with the gym,
and it's the only time
Kuzmenko made the calls.
It's right before Kuzmenko
started saying he had
a lotta cash. Maybe Mostovoi
had something to do with it.
Or maybe he's a friend. Wanna
find the money, track the money.
Find that, then we
can talk about Mustavoi
Muscavoi, whatever his name is.
[cell phone ringing]
- Van Pelt.
- 'Grace.'
- 'Time for the secret meeting.'
- I'll be right there.
The way I see it, we got one
shot at saving Lisbon's job.
[Rigsby]
You think we can?
All we have to do is solve
the murder without Haffner.
Then we take
the murderer to Bertram
use our success as leverage
to get Lisbon back.
- That's not gonna work.
- Come on.
- When have I steered you wrong?
- Recently?
How do we solve
the murder without Haffner?
We catch the killer
before he does.
'Kuzmenko was an athlete.'
He was a compulsive
record keeper.
No doubt that included
very detailed records
of his sexual partners...
probably with a rating system.
'You gotta get into the house'
and you have to find
that list of lovers.
It's probably in an address book
a calendar or a journal.
I don't like it.
It's insubordination.
- 'We're already on the edge.'
- It's for the boss.
This goes wrong, we're out. They
won't give us another chance.
I don't care. I'm in.
Me too.
[intense music]
Okay.
That's the spirit.
[intense music]
[indistinct chattering]
You wanted to know
if Jane is doing anything.
[music continues]
Take a seat.
[instrumental music]
Thank you for doing this.
I don't mind, Teresa.
Bertram has treated you poorly.
Not that he solicits
my opinion on such matters.
Why do you wanna
talk to Sally Carter?
I wanna ask her some
questions about Red John.
Hmm.
She hasn't spoken since
her arrest, not to anyone
so set your
expectations accordingly.
Just so you know, um..
...I am leaving
the Major Crimes Unit
returning to
professional services.
Was always
a temporary assignment.
Well, good luck to you.
Thank you.
It was...interesting..
...working with
you and Jane.
I think that's the polite word
for what it was, but thanks.
Open it up.
[clanks]
Mrs. Carter.
'Mrs. Carter.'
Get a medical team here!
[woman shouting indistinctly]
[woman on PA]
'Medical team
to cell C-38.'
to cell C-3-8.'
[alarm blaring]
"All prisoners,
return to your cells.'
[blaring continues]
How?
She got ahold of a spoon
sharpened the shaft
slit her wrists and throat.
What are you doing here?
Came to ask her if her
husband was Red John.
- Because you need convincing.
- Nice try.
Turns out I didn't need to ask.
She left a note.
"My life began the day I met
"the Lord and master
of my heart, Red John.
Now that he is dead,
all is shadows and silence."
She goes on.
Yeah, it's a bit purple.
Let me see.
[intense music]
See?
You did it.
You killed Red John.
- Jane--
- Shh! I'm reading.
[music continues]
[muttering indistinctly]
So how was the therapist?
Talking about what happened
just makes me feel worse.
I'm not gonna
see her anymore.
Grace, you need counseling.
The job says so.
It could be
a spiritual adviser.
You know, my godfather's
a Presbyterian minister.
- He'll sign the forms for me.
- You think that's a good idea?
Yeah, I do.
I got this.
[instrumental music]
[rattling]
Agents?
Looking for this?
So I found this hidden
in Kuzmenko's bedroom.
Fourteen of his clients are
named in it, with sexual details
'and some kind of
coded rating system.'
There's a really good chance
that one of these
women killed him.
But you weren't gonna
tell me that, were you?
Probably not. No.
Right.
You wanted to solve
this one yourself.
Uh...that was the plan.
[chuckles]
Did you really think
that was gonna happen?
Like I wasn't watching
you every minute?
Jane, I would have
worked with you
if you'd given me the chance.
I'm taking this to Bertram.
Get out.
- He go for it?
- Oh, did he.
Time to break the news.
[instrumental music]
Let me get this straight.
Haffner has the address book,
but it's a fake?
Fake as a three dollar bill.
Then how'd he find it
in Kuzmenko's house?
Well, I copied the names
from the list of
Kuzmenko's clients.
Then I put the book
where Haffner would find it.
I told Haffner Jane thought the
address book was at the house.
- So he went to the house.
- Why?
Haffner's all
about surveillance.
I knew he'd be following us.
I had to do something
to throw him off.
Now we can solve the case
without Haffner watching us.
- No. No, no.
- Don't be hasty.
I will deal
with you in a minute!
When Bertram finds out,
he'll have a coronary.
We knew there was a risk.
Which is why you
shouldn't have done it!
'Go to Haffner and apologize.'
- Tell him it was Jane's fault.
- That hardly seems fair.
Maybe you can convince him
to give you another chance.
- It's not gonna happen.
- She's right.
Oh, God. Why are you doing this?
You were okay. All you had
to do was keep your heads down.
We wanna work for you.
[intense music]
Let me talk to Jane alone.
I could kill you
with my bare hands.
Well, it's not
the first time.
Come on.
You don't have a choice.
You do nothing,
they get fired.
You work with me,
they keep their jobs.
And you might even
get yours back.
Alright, but it's
just you and me.
They don't do anything else.
What's the plan?
Plan is...
we catch the killer.
Kind of obvious.
Jocelyn Chapin.
Patrick Jane.
We're on the verge
of catching the killer
but we'll need your
help to pin him down.
Get a pen and paper. You gotta
get some people to your gym.
We'll need
some of the, shh
the-the glowy spray stuff
the crime scene guys use.
- Glowy spray stuff?
- Yes, the glowy spray stuff.
It's vital.
Got a pen?
We appreciate your help.
Think this will work?
Oh, I'm about 68.2% sure.
Can I have everybody's
attention, please?
Yes, everybody, you, those
with the, uh, ear things.
Uh, yes, could you,
thank you. Sir.
You too. Thank you.
This won't hurt a bit.
My name is Patrick Jane.
This is Teresa Lisbon.
We're investigating
the death of Markus Kuzmenko.
'His killer is somewhere
in this room right now.'
Kuzmenko was struck in
the head with a heavy object.
We believe it was
one of those weights
'from this gym, so we're
gonna test them with a spray'
that can detect trace elements
of blood on a surface by glowing
'even after it's been cleaned.'
We find the weight,
we find our murderer.
So if you could all
sit tight, be patient
the killer will soon
be revealed. Thank you.
- 'Excuse me.'
- Yes.
- Hi. I-I'm an attorney.
- Oh.
Even if you do find blood
on one of those weights
there's no way to connect it
to anyone in this room.
- Ah, fingerprints, my friend.
- 'Fingerprints?'
My fingerprints are
on lots of those weights.
That doesn't mean I
used them to kill anybody.
You make an interesting point.
Okay. Hypothetical.
What if I hid
the weight in my car?
Or my office? My house?
Would that prove
I was the killer?
I-if you found the murder
weapon in my car, yeah.
- Is it in your car?
- No.
No, I knew it wasn't in your
car, because it's in her car.
- 'Right, Jocelyn?'
- What?
The weight you
used to kill Markus.
You hid it in your car when we
told you we were coming over.
- No.
- Oh, please.
You practically
jumped out of your skin
at the mention of "car."
- No, I didn't.
- 'Yes, you did.'
- Yes, you did.
Okay. There's only one
way we can settle this.
Shall we?
What's this?
It's a kettlebell.
I keep it in my trunk
for visits to clients' houses.
[hissing]
'Can you explain why
it has blood on it?'
Ms. Chapin, I just spoke
to a man named Oleg Mostovoi.
He's a loan shark.
He said a few days
before the murder
he loaned Kuzmenko $75,000
and that Kuzmenko said he needed
the money to start his own gym.
Is that why you killed him,
he was gonna compete with you?
I heard from a realtor
that Markus was
looking at gym spaces.
My gym isn't doing
so well anymore
so if he would...would have
left and...taken his clients
I wouldn't have
been able to stay open.
You confronted him.
I begged him to stay.
I mean, it's embarrassing.
I...I said that
he shouldn't leave
because of what
we meant to each other.
And he just looked at me
like he had no idea
what I was talking about.
I mean,
he'd just forgotten.
I suppose there had been
that many girls since.
Oh, and then
he remembered later
and he was charming,
of course, but..
...I just...I just couldn't
help remember that look..
...like I'd been deleted.
And so I went to his house
and I waited for him.
[grunts]
[panting]
You know, I-I don't
know why I did it. I..
I've been on this
super strict diet.
'You know, it messes
with your blood sugar.'
Maybe that's it.
Ray, you told me
that this book
contained the names
of many politically
prominent women
who were carrying on affairs
with the victim in your case
and your killer was
likely one of these women.
Yeah, which is
a PR nightmare. Right?
So I called the leadership
of both parties to warn them
that we-we might have to act
on this because the one thing
they hate more than bad news
is being surprised by it.
But then...lo and behold
I find out that-that-that
the names in here are forged.
'There's no scandal.'
'No, the book didn't even'
belong to the victim.
It's yours, I assume.
Uh, yeah, if I could.
Uh, thank you.
'I hate raising false alarms.'
It makes me feel so foolish
which I suppose was the point.
- Well, maybe--
- Okay, if I may, sir--
No, you may not.
Now, Ray, I-I thought
that you could handle Jane.
'Well, we all make mistakes.'
But we'll find something else
for you to do. Don't worry.
[sighs]
Now...I have a problem.
Because, uh, our urgent
need for your skills
is precisely balanced
by my desire to fire you
before you
destroy the bureau
or my career.
Or both.
I understand.
Mm. You're in a tough spot.
You know who's always,
uh, been a very, uh
healthy moderating
influence on me?
[chuckles]
Yeah. Of course.
Lisbon.
I'm sorry.
Not possible.
Well, then..
...you will continue
to have a problem.
[instrumental music]
- Hey.
- Hey yourself.
- You settling back in?
- Almost.
- Yeah.
- How'd you do it?
Get Bertram to come around?
Oh, wasn't so hard.
Rational discussion
between two reasonable men.
[chuckling]
Rational discussion. I bet.
Mm-hmm.
But, uh...
by all means...go ahead.
I'm sorry?
Say it.
I won't get embarrassed.
Say what?
[whistling]
Oh. You mean say thank you?
Oh...you're welcome.
Was it so hard?
The thing is,
not dealing with you every day
has been very
restful for me.
My back pain's gone.
I sleep really well.
So, I'm actually not so sure
I'm grateful to be back.
You're a terrible liar.
No offense. Good, honest
people always bad liars.
Which makes you what?
Jane? Security just called.
They've got someone
waiting for you downstairs.
Name's Rosalind Harker.
- Thanks, Grace.
- No problem.
The woman that lived with
Red John three
or four years ago?
They didn't actually
live together.
Uh, he was more
the gentleman caller.
- What are you seeing her for?
- Great to have you back.
What are you doing, Jane?
[door squeaks]
Thanks for agreeing
to this, Rosalind.
I wasn't busy.
Besides, it sounded urgent.
It is, in a way.
Are you still playing piano?
Not really. I'm tired
of playing for myself.
- I think I need an audience.
- Okay, it's just here.
And through a doorway
to the right.
Something the matter?
[inhales deeply]
Just a chill.
- Let's go.
- Okay.
[rattling]
No one claimed the body?
That's so sad.
You'd think they'd have
done something with it.
There must be a waiting
period or something.
Yeah, something like that.
You understand..
he never called himself
Red John to me.
The man I knew
was Roy Tagliaferro.
Roy and Red John
are the same person.
I'm sure of it.
Is this him?
I never met this man.
I have no idea who he is.
Thank you.
[intense music]
[rattling]
[theme music]